Courtney Songco

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer with proven experience in creating several cross-browser compatible and responsive websites. Graduated with an AS in Computer Science. Adept in the creative field and can easily adapt to collaborative or self-learning environments.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C++

Applications and Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, VSCode

Other Skills: Product Management, UI/UX Design, Web Design, Front-End Web Development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Designer and Developer

Various Clients

Remote | 04/2022-Current

- Updated landing pages, product pages, and contact forms for clientele's websites.
- Developed over 20 pages by writing lines of code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and other languages.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity, and effectiveness.
- Create and maintain software documentation.
- Surveyed consumers and users preferences in order to improve user experience, including more efficient loading time, better site navigation, and color palette schemes/font styles that are inclusive towards those with visual impairments.
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies and industry trends and apply them to the client's website operations.
- Provided ongoing website maintenance and updates, including bug fixes, security patches, and content updates.

Workforce Development Program Trainee

NASA L'SPACE Mission Concept Academy

Phoenix, *AZ* | 01/2022 – 04/2022

- Lead Administration Officer and assistant software designer for my designated team in NASA L'SPACE 2022.
- Developed a Preliminary Design Review (PDR) exploring and developing in-situ resources for the Artemis mission to the mission South Pole of the Moon.
- Attended weekly webinars hosted by numerous software and hardware engineers discussing about the
 implementation of JMARS which is a Java-developed program that is used in NASA's mission planning to detect
 topographic profiles for data analysis.

EDUCATION

Mt. San Jacinto College- Menifee, CA

AS-T Computer Science | 2022-2023 (Graduated with Honor Distinction)

Awards: Consistent Dean's Lister and President's List | Member of MSJC's Honors Society | Member of Phi Theta Kappa-BDO Chapter